他在哪里?
Where is he?
我下一次不会轻轻地问了
I shan't ask you politely next time.
布洛费在那里?
Where is Blofeld?
开...开...
Cai... Cai...
开罗!
Cairo!
发牌
Cards.
再发
Hit me.
给机会
One chance.
我到哪里可找到他?
Where can I find him?
马丽...
Marie...
问马丽
Ask Marie.
你是谁?
Who are you?
我是詹姆斯邦德
My name is Bond. James Bond.
有什么事要我帮忙吗?
Is there something I can do for you?
是的 确是有事你能帮忙
Yes, as a matter of fact, there is.
我要你说出一件事
There is something I'd like you to get off your chest.
恩斯 布洛费在那里?
Where is Ernst Stavro Blofeld?
大声一点 达令 我听不到
Speak up, darling. I can't hear you.
现在到了第四阶段 鼻子部分
We now come to phase four: The nose.
依我看来 这是整形易容的最困难之部分
In my opinion, the most difficult part of a plastic transformation.
我要你今晚作好手术
I want the operation done tonight.
- 但是… - 没有时间了
- But, ser... - There's no time left.
布先生这是很精密手术
But, Ser Blofeld,this is a most delicate procedure.
就在今晚!
Tonight!
让温度保持在80度
Keep the temperature at precisely 80 degrees.
在玩泥巴 007?
Making mud pies, 007?
他本来几天之后就可以当我
He "would" have been me in a matter of days
如果你给他机会的话
if you'd given the poor fellow a chance.
真是可惜 我好想看手术的成果
Such a pity. I was dying to see how the operation turned out.
去拿他的枪
Get his gun.
别动 手举起
Hold it! Get your hands up.
杀了他!
Kill him!
欢迎到地狱 布洛费
Welcome to hell, Blofeld.
《007系列之金刚钻》
南非之星
Star of South Africa.
未琢磨83.5克拉
83.5 carats rough.
切割47.5克拉
47.5 carats cut.
柏夏之王 未琢磨116克拉
The Akbar Shah. 116 carats rough.
你在听吗? 007
Are you paying attention, 007?
柏夏之王未琢磨116克拉
The Akbar Shah, 116 carats rough.
但实在没必要让我们的部门
But surely, sir, there's no need to bring in our section
办这种简单的走私案件
on a relatively simple smuggling matter.
但唐纳爵士说服首相不这么想
Sir Donald has convinced the PM otherwise.
容我提醒你 布洛费死了
May I remind you, 007,that Blofeld's dead.
结束了
Finished!
起码我们现在能期望你 做点明白 实在的工作
The least we can expect from you now is a little plain, solid work.
早安 各位
Good morning, gentlemen.
- 唐纳爵士现在接见二位 - 谢谢
- Sir Donald will see you now. - Thank you.
早安 爵士
Good morning, Sir Donald.
- 这位是邦德中尉 - 你好 邦德中尉 请坐下
- This is Commander Bond. - How do you do? Please sit down.
- 雪利酒? -  谢谢 我不喝 医生规定的
- Sherry? - Not for me, thanks. Doctor's orders.
- 邦德中尉? - 好的 谢谢
- Commander Bond? - Yes, thank you.
听说你正在休假中
You've been on holiday, I understand.
希望很轻松愉快
Relaxing, I hope.
并不轻松 但非常令人满意
Hardly relaxing but... most satisfying.
干杯 干杯
Cheers.
是索拉利中的上品
Pity about your liver, sir.It's an unusually fine Solera.
- 我想是51年分的 - 雪利酒并没有年分的 007
- '51, I believe. - There is no year for sherry, 007.
我指的是雪利酒最初的酒基
I was referring to the original vintage on which the sherry is based, sir.
1851年
1851.
是吧
Unmistakable.
一点也不错
Precisely.
请问你 中尉 对于宝石
Tell me, Commander.
你的专业知识到何种程度?
How far does your expertise extend into the field of diamonds?
自然界所发现的最硬物质 可以切割水晶 令人联想婚姻
Hardest substance found in nature.They cut glass. Suggest marriage.
能代替狗成为女人最好朋友 大约就是这些了
They've replaced a dog as a girl's best friend. That's about it.
很新鲜听到你有一件事不是专家
Refreshing to hear there's "one" subject you're not an expert on.
也许我最好简短说明一下我们问题的背景
Perhaps I'd better give you a brief background into our problem.
全世界百分八十之宝石来自南非矿区
Eighty per cent of the world's diamonds come from mines in South Africa.
大部分掘自地底含宝石之泥土
Most are dug out of shafts of diamond-bearing clay
深度可达地底三千尺
at depths of up to 3,000 feet.
整个过程从头到尾 是在极端严密的安全系统下进行
The whole process, from start to finish,is subject to an airtight security system.
这是必要的预防措施
It's an essential precaution,
纵然业界深以他们工人的忠心及尽职为傲
though the industry prides itself on the loyalty and devotion of its workers.
当然安全措施能确保忠心
Naturally the security measures tend to ensure that loyalty,
如同我们提供的社区及社会福利
as do the extensive amenities and social services we provide.
有长驻之医生及护士
There's a permanent staff of doctors, nurses,
甚至牙医
even dentists.
整个过程从头至尾 是在极端严密的安全系统下进行
The whole process, from start to finish,is subject to an airtight security system.
这是必要的预先防范
It's a necessary precaution,
纵然业界深以他们工人忠心及尽职为傲
though the industry prides itself on the loyalty and devotion of its workers.
下一位!
Next!
毒虫
The scorpion.
是自然界最棒的杀手 温特先生
Mother nature's finest killer, Mr Wint.
向大师学习永远不晚 其特先生
One is never too old to learn from a master, Mr Kidd.
医生 晚安
Dr Tynan? Good evening.
你是谁? 乔呢?
Who are you? And where is Joe?
乔今晚不能来
Joe couldn't make it tonight.
我是温特先生
I'm Mr Wint.
这位是其特先生
This is Mr Kidd.
我明白了
I see.
他怎么了?
What's the matter with him?
我的智齿 还没拔掉
It's my wisdom teeth.I haven't had 'em out yet.
请你看一下好吗? 医生
Would you mind having a look, Doctor?
没问题
Of course.
我不会弄痛你的 张开
I'm not going to hurt you. Just open.
不 再张大一点
No, no. Open wide.
真奇怪
Curious
碰那些宝石的人似乎都难逃一死
how everyone who touches those diamonds seems to... die.
- 站住 你们是谁? - 医生派我们来的
- Stop right there! Who are you? - Dr Tynan sent us.
- 他自己为何不来? - 他生病了
- Why didn't he come himself? - He was taken sick.
被虫咬了
Bitten by the bug.
他送这个给你
He sent this for you.
如果上帝要让人飞
If God had wanted man to fly...
他会给人双翼的 其特先生
He would have given him wings, Mr Kidd.
当然 没有安全系统是完美的
No security system is perfect.
我们都接受有走私带出的可能
We've always accepted a percentage of smuggling.
但这二年来 纵然我们有一切防范措施 走私率却高升得惊人
But over the past two years, despite all our precautions, it's gone up alarmingly.
更惊人的是 失踪之宝石没有一个出现在市场
And none of the stones have reached the market.
唐纳爵士怀疑有人屯积
Sir Donald thinks someone's stockpiling.
我们更担心的是有人可能要卖宝石 降低价钱
Our concern is that someone might dump them on the market to depress prices or...
要不就是以此向你们永远威胁
Make you agree to perpetual blackmail.
说得正是
Exactly.
我们要知道是
What we need to know is
谁在屯积
who the stockpilers are.
U这个字母
The letter U
就是雨伞的第一个字母
is for umbrella.
我们带着伞 以防下雨
We take it lest it rain.
希望我们到家前
We hope we shan't want it
不会没伞
till we're home again.
二个男人来见你 夫人
Two men to see you, missy.
是男士 乔苏
Gentlemen, Joshua.
我很快就回来 孩子们 乔苏会念故事书给你们听
I shan't be long, children.Joshua is going to read you a story.
真高兴再度见到你们!
How nice to see you again!
- 这次去哪里? - 阿姆斯特丹
- Where to this time? - Amsterdam.
阿母斯特丹! 太好了!
Amsterdam! Oh, how lovely!
我可以替孩子们带回运河的照片
I shall have to bring back some pictures of the canals for the children.
好的 没问题
Ask, and ye shall receive, Mrs Whistler.
今天的课就到此结束 男士们
Thus endeth the lesson for today, gentlemen.
南非最近数件谋杀案让事情更加复杂
Several recent murders in South Africa have complicated matters.
如果他们在我们发现他们前
If they shut down operations before we discover them...
结束作业对我们将是个灾难
It would be catastrophic for us
对政府也是
and for the government.
- 我一直很想到南非 - 你要去荷兰
- I've always fancied a trip to South Africa. - You're going to Holland.
- 我们跟踪一走私犯许久了 - 他叫彼得.法蓝
- For some time we've had our eyes on a smuggler  - Peter Franks.
他要前往阿母斯特丹
He's due to leave for Amsterdam.
我们知道他的接货人吗?
Do we know who his contacts are?
你不在时我们仍然工作 中尉
We do function in your absence, Commander.
护照 先生?
Passport, sir?
法蓝先生 护照室有你的口信
Mr Franks. There's a message for you at Passport Control.
那边那道门 你可以把车停在外面
That door over there.you can park outside.
谢谢
Thank you.
法蓝先生
Mr Franks...
你的护照没有问题
Your passport is quite in order.
任何人看你这身穿着 马丽
Anyone seeing you in that outfit, Moneypenny
一定不舍得离开呢
would certainly be discouraged from leaving the country.
要我从荷兰带给你什么?
What can I bring you back from Holland?
一个宝石
A diamond?
装饰在戒指上
In a ring
金香花如何?
Would you settle for a tulip?
好的
Yes.
(水翼船)
前面是阿母斯特丹最古老一座桥
Ahead is one of the oldest bridges in Amsterdam.
叫无钱桥
The Skinny Bridge.
桥建于三百年前
It was built over 300 years ago
是一对想天天互相见面姐妹所建
by two sisters who wanted to visit each other every day.
不幸的是 他们用尽了钱 所以这座桥叫无钱桥
Unfortunately they ran out of money. So that is why it is called the Skinny Bridge.
在各位右手边漂亮的路边房
On your right,those beautiful old houses
可见于我国知名画家林布兰画中
can be seen in the paintings of our famous painter, Rembrandt.
现在我们沿阿母斯特丹河而下
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
请大家看左边你们可以看到…
if you will look to your left as we go down the Amstel, you can see...
伟太太说要带运河照片给孩子看
Mrs Whistler did want some pictures of the canals for the children.
你真好 其特先生
How kind of you, Mr Kidd.
孩子们一定很惊喜的
The children will be so thrilled.
什么事?
Yes?
彼得 法蓝
Franks. Peter Franks.
上来 三楼
Come up. Third floor.
不要客气 我马上好
Make yourself at home! I'll be out in a minute!
自己倒酒喝
Help yourself to a drink!
凯斯先生在吗?
Is Mr Case not at home?
没有凯斯先生 T是指帝凡内
There is no Mr Case. The T is for Tiffany.
帝凡内.凯斯
Tiffany Case?
的确不同凡响
Definitely distinctive.
我在那里出生的 在一楼
I was born there, on the first floor,
我妈正在物色结婚戒指
while my mother was looking for a wedding ring.
我替你高兴幸好不是凡克里阿皮特店
I'm glad for your sake it wasn't Van Cleef and Arpels.
我进来时你不是金发吗?
Weren't you a blonde when I came in?
可能
Could be.
我常会注意这类小事 一个女孩是金发还是黑发
I tend to notice little things like that. Whether a girl is a blonde or a brunette.
你喜欢那一个呢?
And which do you prefer?
只要颜色和衣服搭配得好
Providing the collars and cuffs match...
我们等一下再谈这个
We'll talk about that later.
把杯子给我
Let me have your glass.
我替你加冰块
I'll get you some ice.
你老是穿得这种几乎不蔽体衣服很不赖 我赞同
That's quite a nice little nothing you're almost wearing. I approve.
我穿衣不用人意见的
I don't dress for the hired help.
让我看你的护照 法蓝
Let's see your passport, Franks.
职业 运输顾问
Occupation: Transport consultant?
太可爱了一点吧!
That's a little cute, isn't it?
- 我去穿完衣服 - 没关系 请不要为了我
- I'll finish dressing. - Please don't. Not on my account.
我不太喜欢红发 很可怕的气质
I don't care much for redheads. Terrible tempers.
但它却适合你
But somehow it seems to suit you.
我本来的头发
It's my own.
但它需要一点温和的
But it is in need of some soft lighting.
- 而我知道一家小餐厅… - 我从不把公事和玩乐混在一起
- I know a little restaurant... - I never mix business with pleasure.
- 我也一样 - 很好
- Neither do I. - Good!
言归正传了把你的玩笑话留到把宝石安全送到洛杉矶再说
Then save the cute remarks until after you get the diamonds into Los Angeles.
- 宝石现在在那里? - 那不是你的问题
- Where are they now? - That's not your problem.
你的问题是把宝石弄进去
Your problem is getting them in.
- 有多少? - 五万卡拉
- How much is there? - 50,000 carats.
以142卡拉为一央斯 这可是相当大数量的宝石 这可不简单
At 142 carats an ounce, that's an awful lot of ice. That won't be easy.
所以才付你五万元
That's why you're being paid 50 grand.
你以为会是什么? 一付耳圈?
What did you think it was going to be? A pair of earrings?
还有 法蓝 看在老天分上 想一点新鲜的方法
And, Franks, for God's sakes, come up with something original.
我得佩服你 Q 非常高明
I've got to hand it to you, Q. Quite ingenious.
只是个小构想很容易就想出来
An obvious little notion. Thought it might come in handy.
对了 M一直想联络你 那个彼得.法蓝逃走了
M's been trying to get in touch with you. That Peter Franks fellow's escaped.
他在往伦敦的路上杀了一名警卫
Killed one of the guards on the way up to London.
喂?
Hello?
喂!
Hello!
你还在听吗?
Are you there?
- 什么事? - 彼得.法蓝
- Yes? - Peter Franks.
三楼
Third floor.
- 晚安 - 晚安
- Guten Abend. - Good evening.
请
Bitte.
- 你是英国人? - 对 我是英国人
- You are English? - Yes, I'm English.
我会说英语
I speak English.
- 你是那一楼? - 三楼
- Who is... your floor? - Three, please.
他死了吗?
Is he dead?
我真心希望如此
I sincerely hope so.
- 他是谁? - 不知道
- Who is he? - No idea.
他跟踪了我一天
This chap's been following me all day today.
我的天
My God!
你杀了詹姆斯邦德
You've just killed James Bond!
就是他呀?
Is that who it was?
这证明没人是打不倒的
It just proves no one's indestructible.
你不能杀了邦德 坐等警察来呀
You don't kill James Bond and wait around for the cops to arrive!
我们得快把宝石弄走
We've got to get those diamonds out of here fast!
在那里?
Where are they?
昨天早上一个老太太送来的
A little old lady dropped them by yesterday morning.
无价之宝
Priceless.
我想应该让邦德先生替我们送货
I think we ought to let Mr Bond carry the load from here on out.
真是好笑
It's funny.
一个人有许多话要对他兄弟说时 结果总是太迟了
All the things one wanted to say to one's brother... when it's all too late.
让我再次致上我最深的慰问之意
Let me assure you of our deepest condolences.
请你登
Would you please board the aircraft?
- 我们一向分不开的 - 请登机 法蓝先生
- We were inseparable, you know. - Please, Mr Franks.
飞往洛杉矶 之LH450班将起飞
Lufthansa announce the departure of flight LH450 to Los Angeles.
请系安全带 升空前勿抽烟
Please fasten your seat belts, and no smoking until airborne.
谢谢
Thank you.
他们都上来了 凯斯小姐确实很迷人
They're both aboard. I must say, Miss Case seems quite attractive.
以一个女人来说
For a lady.
从阿姆斯特丹的LH450班飞机将抵达
Lufthansa announce the arrival of flight LH450 from Amsterdam...
- 法蓝先生? - 是的
- Mr Franks? - Yes.
请跟我到海关
Follow me to Customs, please.
彼得.法蓝 杰瑞
Peter Franks, Jerry.
去吃午餐吧! 杰瑞我来接
Get some lunch, Jerry. I'll take over.
请拿出死亡证明书
Death certificate, please, Mr Franks.
非利.赖特 你这骗子
Well, well, well! Felix Leiter, you old fraud.
谨代表CIA欢迎来美国
On behalf of the CIA, welcome to America.
有人派车来接你
Someone sent their brain trust down to meet you.
我放弃 我知道宝石在身体中
I give up. I know the diamonds are in the body,
但在哪里?
but where?
消化管 赖特医生
Alimentary, Dr Leiter.
再见 詹姆斯 保持联络
So long, James. Keep in touch.
你其他的行李检查好了 好了 各位!
The rest of your luggage has been cleared, Mr Franks. OK, fellas!
你想坐在前座吗? 法蓝先生
You wanna sit in the front, Mr Franks?
前面空位比较大 法蓝先生
It's a lot smoother ride in the front, Mr Franks.
好的 我坐前面
Yes, I believe I'll sit in front.
那死人… 后座的死者
The stiff... "deceased" back there.
是你弟弟吗?
Your brother, Mr Franks?
是的
Yes, it was.
我也有弟弟
I got a brudder.
世界真小
Small world.
法蓝先生 我是莫顿.史浪博
Mr Franks, I'm Morton Slumber.
在这令人难过的时刻请接受我诚心的慰问之意
Please accept my heartfelt condolences at this most difficult hour.
他是走向更好的世界
He is heading for a better world, Mr Slumber.
想到这一点令人感到心慰
There is some consolation in that.
那么现在 准备让死者作最后之旅
Now then, if we're ready to begin the final journey...
愿他灵魂安息
May his soul rest in peace.
对 阿门
Oh, yes. Amen.
请跟我到我的办公室 我会把骨灰缶交给你
If you'd come into my comfortable office, we will bring you the urn.
我很高兴你选择我们史浪博葬仪公司
I'm so happy you chose our half-couch, hinged-panel, slumber-on casket.
我相信你弟弟会赞同这选择
I'm sure your brother would have appreciated it.
我想他一定会的
I'm sure he did.
请坐
Please, be seated.
回归尘土
Ashes to ashes...
- 回归尘土 - 正是
- Dust to dust. - Exactly.
在这个时刻…我相信你希望独处静思
At a moment like this, I'm sure you'd rather be left alone, for reflection.
你设想真周到
Most thoughtful.
我们替你弟弟选了安静的地方在追思园中
We've selected a private niche for your brother in our Garden of Remembrance.
是用金色窗布遮住的 你一定能找得到
The one with the restful chartreuse curtains and Angel's Breath gold trim.
希望你认为一切安排得宜
I hope you'll find everything in order.
你们的安排必是没有问题的
The arrangements have been impeccable
到目前为止
so far.
非常...感人
Very... moving.
令人感动 温先生
Heart-warming, Mr Wint.
闪耀的致敬 其先生
A glowing tribute, Mr Kidd.
你这下流背信玩诈的英国佬 那些宝石是假的
You dirty, double-crossin' limey fink! Those goddamn diamonds are phonies!
不要告诉我
No, don't tell me. You're St Peter?
你是圣彼得 是吧 都是珠子 真的宝石呢?
Paste! Glass! Where's the real stuff, Franks?
真的钱呢? 什么意思? 你不会烧掉五万元的真币吧!
Where's the real money? You wouldn't burn 50,000 "real" dollars, would you?
最后一次问你 真的宝石呢?
One last break. Where are the real diamonds?
你给我真币
You get me the real money
我就把真的宝石给你们
and I'll bring you the real diamonds.
你要去那儿?
Where do you think you're goin'?
我听说热带城旅馆很好
I hear that the Hotel Tropicana is quite comfortable.
我的慰问之意 二位
My condolences, gentlemen.
非利
Hello, Felix.
一切很好 但只有一个问题
Very comfortable. But there's one problem.
我要真货 而且要很快拿到
I want the real merchandise  rather quickly.
Q带着刚刚才到达 我们明早就去拿
Q has just arrived with it. We'll be up with them in the morning.
你最好乖乖地待在那儿 没有必要惹麻烦
So I'd sit tight if I were you. There's no sense in looking for trouble.
你就享受一下 詹姆斯 我相信你知道如何享受
Just enjoy yourself, James. I'm sure you know how.
对 我也许先淋个浴或什么的
Quite. I'll probably take in a show.
(白屋旅馆 谢地树脱口秀)
(谢地树)
到目前为止你们还喜欢吗?
How do you like me so far?
人家说我有洛赫孙的身材
People say I have the body of Rock Hudson.
你们见过我大怒的情形吗?
If he ever finds out what I'm doin' to it, he'll be madder than hell.
我把这些女孩叫作我的橡头宝宝
I call these girls my Acorns.
其实他们是威乐怀特送给我的 他现在正在上面某处
Actually, they're a gift from Willard Whyte, who is upstairs right now
用真正的大楼玩大富翁游戏
playing Monopoly with real buildings.
我想打电话给他 但想要找到威乐怀特
Tryin' to find Willard Whyte is like tryin' to find a virgin in a maternity ward.
就像在产妇室找处女一样难 谨代表白屋 我要告诉你们
On behalf of the Whyte House, I wanna let you folks know
你们是很差劲的观众
you've been a lousy audience.
所以滚开吧! 待会见
So get lost. See ya later.
谢地 树
Shady Tree!
- 谢地 我们真是仰慕你呀! - 多么有格调 品味!
- Shady, we just adored your act! - What taste, style!
我们有几点建议
And we have a few suggestions.
我不需要批评家 我40年未改变我的表演
Critics and material I don't need! I haven't changed my act in 40 years.
站住! 不要进去
Hold it! Don't go in there.
我们没拿到真的宝石 所以我们需要树 活着
We didn't get the real diamonds, so we need Tree, alive.
这最令人困恼
That's most annoying.
- 下注! - 厢式货车 输家
- Get down there! - Crap. Boxcar, the loser.
好了 小猫 你都输光了
That's it, pussycat. I shot the whole wad.
你说怎么样? 到我那边?
What do you say? Back to my place?
你人不错 麦西 真的 你人很不错
You're a nice person, Maxie. Really, you are.
你何不去睡个觉? 我们明年再见
Why don't you go and take a nap? And I'll see you next year.
我要五千元赌金 不 一万好了
May I have $5,000? No, make it $10,000.
二千元限制
$2,000 limit.
有什么问题吗?
Is there some problem?
沙斯比先生
Mr Saxby.
这位先生要一万元的信用 二千元限制
Gentleman wants $10,000 credit with a $2,000 limit.
我是法蓝
My name is Franks.
彼得 法蓝
Peter Franks.
法蓝先生有足够信用
Mr Franks' credit's good.
- 祝你好运 - 谢谢 我要二垒
- Good luck to you, Mr Franks. - Thank you. I'll have two stacks now.
这里四千元
Give the gentleman 4,000.
谢谢!
Thank you.
我是番帝
Hi! I'm Plenty.
- 你当然是了 - 番帝.奥图
- But of course you are. - Plenty O'Toole.
是取自你爸爸的名字吧?
Named after your father, perhaps?
你要我帮忙吗? 我是指玩牌
Would you like some help? On the craps, I mean.
你人真好
That's very kind of you.
下注吧! 下注吧!
Coming out. Coming out.
女士抛股 女士走运
Next shooter is a lady. Ladies are lucky. For the lady.
九 九点
Nine. Mark nine.
七点 女士出局
Seven, loser. The lucky lady craps out.
再来一盘 法蓝先生你抛
New shooter. Your shot, Mr F.
- 我是威乐.怀特 - 树死了 转到二号
- Willard Whyte speakin'. - Tree is dead. Turn on number two.
是彼得.法蓝
It's Peter Franks.
是十号
Hard ten. Ten's the number.
我押十号二百元
I'll take the full odds on the ten. 200 on the hard way.
限制金押单数 250元押11 谢谢
The limit on all the numbers, 250 on the eleven. Thank you very much.
你以前玩过这个呢!
Say! You've played this game before!
只玩过一次
Just once.
- 现在我们怎么办? - 不要拿细节烦我 伯特!
- Now what do we do? - Don't bother me with details, Bert!
给我弄到宝石就是了!
Just get me the diamonds!
你玩得真熟练 就像猴子玩果子一样
You handle those cubes like a monkey handles coconuts.
谢谢 各位 谢谢你们一流的服务
Thank you, gentlemen, for such a sterling service.
你赢了五万元呀!
That's 50,000 dollars!
减掉给你的五千元 我还有四万五千元 谢谢你
Minus $5,000 for you... leaves me $45,000, and thank you very much.
那没什么 真的!
It was nothing, really!
你知道吗 彼得.法蓝? 你这人真不赖!
You know something, Peter Franks? You're a terrific guy!
虽然有点怪 但人真的很不错
A little weird, but a terrific guy!
我们去找个地方喝一杯如何?
Why don't we go someplace and have a drink?
喝一杯?
A drink?
如果你想进来 番帝
If you'd like to come in, Plenty.
好漂亮! 你这里真棒!
How pretty! What a super place you have!
只要等我一秒钟 爱人
Just give me one second, lover.
晚安
Good evening.
恐怕你们逮到我正不是时候
I'm afraid you've caught me with more than my hands up.
这是怎么回事? 变态者集会不成?
What the hell is this?! A perverts' convention or something?!
听着 你不可以这样对我
You can't do this to me!
住手! 我在这城里有朋友…
Stop that! I've got friends in this town!
准确极了
Exceptionally fine shot.
我不知道下面有泳池
I didn't know there was a pool down there.
好 我们谈公事 我想你们是为真的…
Let's get down to business. I presume you've come for the real...
真的宝石而来
The real diamonds.
晚安 凯斯小姐
Good evening, Miss Case.
很抱歉得罪你的反胃朋友
Sorry about your fulsome friend.
我想你一定失去些什么
I'll bet you really missed something.
今晚也许并不是全然损失
The evening may not be a total loss after all.
我们何不先谈一谈
Why don't we talk a bit first
先?
First?
你想谈什么?
What would you like to talk about?
你选话题
You pick a subject.
- 宝石? - 好孩子!
- Diamonds? - Good boy!
你想知道宝石在那里? 以及我是否单独行动
And you want to know where they are, and whether I'm working alone or not.
到目前为止很很 继续
So far, so good. Keep going.
如果不是一个人 那是跟谁呢
And if not, then with whom.
这样你好通知你的顶头上司
So you can inform your superiors and...
然后取得宝石
acquire the diamonds.
彼得!
Peter!
我真对你印象深刻呀!
I'm very impressed.
你比我预料得要复杂多了
There's a lot more to you than I had expected.
可以推测 我是死刑犯
Presumably I'm the condemned man,
而显然地 你是那顿早餐后
and obviously you're the hearty breakfast.
对吗?
Right?
你不打算告诉我宝石所在 对吧?
You're not going to tell me where the diamonds are, are you?
什么宝石?
What diamonds?
你迟早要说的
Sooner or later you'll have to talk.
他们会让你张口的
They'll make you.
最起码你无法活着离开这里
At the very least, you'll never get out of town alive.
我可以解决这小问题
I can solve that little problem.
那我很幸运 碰上你
It's lucky for me that I ran into you.
我们对半分
Fifty-fifty split.
你拿宝石 我负责让我们离开这里
You get the diamonds, I get us out.
我们?
Us?
我不能帮了你又留下来呀!
I can't very well help you and then stick around.
我们明晚前就能搭
We could be on a plane and out of the country by tomorrow night.
里约...香港...
Rio... Hong Kong...
我认识香港一个很好的交易商
I know a good tailor in Hong Kong.
香港
Hong Kong.
好吧! 我去拿宝石 你去拿机票
All right. I'll get the diamonds, you get the plane tickets.
不 机场太明显了
No. The airport's too obvious.
我安排了汽车让我们离开
A rented car should do us fine for openers.
设想周全
That's good thinking.
而且既然你是被监视的人 我去拿宝石 你负责车子
And since you're the one being watched, I'll get the diamonds, you get the car.
设想非常周全
That's very good thinking.
彼得
Oh, Peter!
我有个感觉 我们会开始有个很愉快的关系
I have a feeling this is the beginning of a wonderful relationship.
达令
Darling...
我去哪里拿宝石?
Where do I pick up the diamonds?
你最后一次到马戏团是什么时候?
When was the last time you visited a circus?
马戏团 马戏团
Circus Circus proudly presents
骄傲地呈现空中飞人表演
the Flying Palacios!
- 他进来了 - 好 待命
- She's in the building. - Right. Stand by.
詹姆斯 下次请站着时选接谈地点
James, next time, pick a contact point when you're standing up.
- 非利 如果他溜掉… - 别紧张 我有30个探员在下面
- Felix, if she gives your men the slip... - Relax. I have 30 agents down there.
他就算穿上球靴也逃不掉
A mouse with sneakers on couldn't get through.
给麦斯信号
Give Maxwell his cue.
这里是四分卫
This is Quarterback.
传递行动开始
Operation Passover, commence.
四分卫呼叫泰南
Quarterback to Tight End.
传递行动开始
Operation Passover, commence.
知道
Roger.
(你何不去玩水球游戏)
他上路了 目前为止一切顺利
She's on her way. So far, so good.
- 祝好运 非利 待会见 - 你去那里?
- Good luck, Felix. I'll see you later. - Where are you going?
租车中心
The car rental agency.
我们的小约定?
Our little rendezvous?
你以为他真的会去? 只有千分之一可能呢
You don't actually think she'll show up? That's a thousand-to-one shot.
不 不是钱的缘故
No, more like even money.
是他的忠心和我的魅力在较量
Her devotion to larceny versus my... incomparable charm.
好了 你们准备好了吗? 开枪!
All right, kiddies! Ready? Aim! Fire!
我告诉你们吧! 今晚我保证每一次有胜利者
What did I tell you? Didn't I promise you a winner every time?
拿去 年轻人 如何?
There you are, young man.
好了 女孩及男孩们再度开始 你们只要抓好了枪就是了
Boys and girls, here we go again. All you have to do is just take your gun...
这里有位小小姐 有位小男生
Here we have a little lady, here we have a little man,
还有一位大小姐
and here we have a big lady.
你有点超龄了 是吧! 姐妹
You're a little out of your league, aren't ya, sister?
好了 把枪对准 你们知道怎么作
Point the gun. You know what to do.
都准备好了? 预备
All ready? Get set.
抓好等我说开枪
Now hold it till I say go.
开枪
Go!
快呀! 大家对准小丑
Come on! That's it!
每一次都有胜利者
Everybody point right at the clown. A winner every time!
打中它们! 这样才对!
There we are! All right! That's the way to do it!
你们看看! 我们又有胜利者了!
Look at that! And we have another winner!
我们的小玩具狗拿去!
Annie Oakley on the end!
好痛快的一晚! 好痛快一晚!
Here we are. What an eye! What an eye!
等一等! 我都看到了!
Wait a second! I saw the whole thing!
机器预先安排好了! 他是谁 你妈妈不成?
The machine's fixed! Who's she? Your mother?
去你的小鬼!
Blow up your pants!
他只赢了一次他只赢一次!
One win! She only had one win!
应该要24次才能赢到那只狗
You're supposed to have 24 to win that dog!
不要再吵了 好吗?
Will you give it a rest, kid?
好了 男孩女孩们 开始…
All right, boys and girls! Here we go!
这是桑波拉第一次展出 他是全世界最奇怪的女孩
Here for the first time, see Zambora, strangest girl ever born to live.
他在南非奈洛比附近被抓到
She was captured near Nairobi, south Africa,
是人类悲惨经验的一部分
and is believed to be part of a cruel, inhuman experiment.
这个漂亮的女孩将被锁在钢条的笼子内
This beautiful girl will be locked into a steel cage,
就在你们眼前 他将变成凶猛重450旁大人猿
will change very slowly into a ferocious 450-pound gorilla.
请不要动 各位 你们一定要寂静无声
Please be very still, ladies and gentlemen.
我们必须警告你们
We must have absolute silence
才不会打扰桑波拉的转变过程
so we wouldn't disturb Zambora from her transcendental state.
所有科学实验
We must warn you that in every scientific experiment
永远只有危险
there's always a danger.
所以请注意我们出口在那里
So keep in mind those curtains is an exit.
若有紧急事情发生 快离开这里!
God forbid something should go wrong over here, get outta here!
现在要转变了
Now we start the transformation.
很危险 请安静
Very dangerous. Very quiet, please.
我的美人 醒来!
Wake, my beauty, wake!
小姐你不能从这边走 从另一边
Hey, lady, not through there. The other way.
快追
Come on!
- 他没出现? - 非利 不要告诉我你们追丢了他
- No show? - Felix, don't tell me you lost her?
我们追丢了他
We lost her.
你这地方很不错
Nice place you have here.
把衣服脱掉 享受阳光
Take something off. Enjoy the sun.
你还有胆来这里!
You've got a lot of guts showing up here!
让我等了二小时 背都僵硬
Letting me freeze my behind off at a blackjack table for two hours
苦等根本不存在的宝石!
waiting for some nonexistent diamonds!
我的黑假发怎么会在泳池里?
And what the hell is my black wig doing in the pool?!
- 她… - 死了
- She's... - Dead.
本来应该是你 你是下一位连络人
Supposed to be you. The next link in the pipeline.
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
可怜的番帝一定是来找你
Poor Plenty must have stumbled in here looking for you.
我不相信你
I don't believe you.
南非有个牙医死了 还有阿母斯特丹的那老太太
A dentist is dead in South Africa. That little old lady in Amsterdam.
谢地昨晚送命 他们对我失手一次
Shady got his last night. They've missed me once.
而你是下一个
And you're next.
- 你的接谈人是谁? - 你的口气好像警察
- Now, who's your connection? - You sound like a cop...
- 你的接谈人是谁? - 我只知道电话中的声音
- Who's your connection? - All I know is voices on a phone.
他们替我安排这个地方 叫我等候下一步指示
They got me this place and told me to wait for further instructions.
你会发现在水里很难听清楚
You'd find it difficult to hear under water.
- 东西在那里? - 你是谁?
- Now, where's the stuff? - Who are you?
你不是警察 你也不是彼得法蓝
You're not a cop and you're not Peter Franks.
你也不是让人打另一边耳光的人 东西在那里?
You're not the type to turn the other cheek. Where is it?
112航班即将到达 从洛杉矶来的...
Eastern Airlines announce the arrival of flight 112 from Los Angeles,
从第七入口
gate 7.
谢谢
Thank you.
加满 好的
Fill it up, please.
是伯特.沙斯比
It's Bert Saxby.
是威乐.怀特的左右手
Willard Whyte's right-hand man.
你看到顶端吗? 那阁楼?
Do you see the top? The penthouse?
听说怀特在那上面 三年未踏出一步
They say Willard Whyte hasn't set foot out of there in three years.
没人见过他 没有人
And no one has seen him, no one.
- 多少钱? - 这可以付吗?
- How much is that? - Did you pay for this?
抓住他
Cut him off.
卷发 我的收据呢?
Hey, Curly! What about my stamps?
你去那里? 你疯了吗? 让我过
Where are you going? Are you mad? Let me by!
收据 你还没加油呢 可以吧
Stamps? You ain't got no gas yet!
- 好吗 那灌几加伦汽油进去! - 退后呀!
- OK, so shove a coupla gallons in! - Well, back it up.
你继续吵呀 小心有人找你麻烦
Keep leaning on that tooter, Charlie, and you'll get a shot in the mouth!
快呀! 小姐 开走
Come on, lady, move it!
好 小姐 你赢 你赢
OK, lady, you win, you win.
- 麻烦一下谁来搬走那车?! - 照他的话!
- Will someone move that car?! - Do what he says!
我要高级汽油
Hey! I wanted high-test!
算了 卷发 我给你机会了 你自己弄糟了!
Forget it, Curly! You had your chance and you blew it!
好了 教授
OK, Professor.
- 哈喽 - 嗨
- Hello. - Hi.
- 我以前未见过你呢 - 我是赫金谢莫
- I haven't seen you here before. - I'm Klaus Hergersheimer.
- 新来的? - 来了快三年 在G单位
- New here? - I've been here three years. G Section.
G单位现在怎么样?
How are things in G Section?
还是老样子
Still the same old grind. You know.
检查幅射护层 替换了
Checking radiation shields for replacement.
对了 你的呢?
By the way, where's yours?
我等你们送来 等了几天了
I've been waiting a couple of days for you guys to deliver them.
真抱歉 你应该打电话给我们的
Gee, I'm sorry. You should have given us a phone call.
我这里有一个 我常常备用的
Look, I've got one here. Lucky for you, I carry spares.
要一直带着 对幅射不能不小心
You keep that on. You can't be too careful about radiation.
说得对极 带上这个我觉得比较安全
Absolutely. I feel much safer with this on.
再见
See you around.
你是谁? 要作什么?
Who are you? What do you want?
我是赫金谢莫 G单位
Klaus Hergersheimer. G Section.
只是来检查幅射护层的
Just... checking on radiation shields.
让我看看 你是…
Now let me see. You are...
麦斯博士兼教授 我们的护层没问题
Professor Dr Metz. Our shields are fine!
现在出去!
Now get out!
很抱歉 很快就好的
I'm sorry. It won't take a moment but
但我必须证实
I must verify.
麦斯 怎么拼?
Metz. How do you spell it?
M… 请你走开好吗? 讨厌的人
M-E... Will you please leave, you irritating man?
博士 没必要欺负小人物
Doctor, there's no reason to run down the little people.
G单位也许没你们的工作重要
G Section may not be as important to the operation as you are,
但我们也有我们的工作命令
but we do have our orders.
麦斯博士 威乐怀特找你
Dr Metz... Willard Whyte for you.
好 出去 出去
Right. Out, out.
哈罗 WW
Hello, WW.
是的 终于来了
Yes, it's finally here.
足够我们完成的
Quite enough for completion.
我们很快就能做好
We'll be through shortly.
不 完全没有问题
No. No problems at all.
好
Right.
- 你出去好吗? - 好的 博士
- Now will you get out of here?! - Certainly, Doctor.
我看到我要看的了
I've seen everything I need to see.
谢谢
Thank you very much.
对不起打扰 我是赫金谢莫
Hi. Sorry to bother you. I'm Klaus Hergersheimer.
G单位
G Section.
检查幅射护层
Checking radiation shields?
他在那里! 岩石后面!
There he is! Behind the rock!
快追
Come on!
这是干什么? 业余人员之夜?
What is this? Amateur night?
阻止他 哈利!
Stop him, Harry!
让他离开那机器
Get him off that machine.
那不是玩具 快让他离开月球车!
That isn't a toy. Get out of that moon buggy!
这简直是疯狂!
It's gone berserk!
你在作什么?
Hey, what do you think you're doin'?!
那边!
That way!
- 怎么回事? - 快上车!
- What happened? The diamonds... - Get in the car!
如果你看到一个人 是个教授 微笑就对了!
If you see a mad professor in a minibus, just smile!
布林 接警长办公室
Fred, get the sheriff's office.
你可以在下个角落让我下车 这整件事情越来越走样了
Drop me off at the next corner. This is getting out of hand.
但你要开始和威乐怀特打交道
When you start stealing moon machines from Willard Whyte,
那就是再见 祝好运
goodbye and good luck!
别紧张 我朋友非利他能摆平一切事情
Just relax. I have a friend named Felix who can fix anything.
他结婚了吗?
Is he married?
那就是那个破坏者
There goes that son-of-a-bitchin' saboteur!
别紧张 你有个朋友叫非利可以摆平一切事
Relax! You've got a friend named Felix who can fix anything.
不幸的是 怀特也能
Unfortunately, so can Willard Whyte.
可恶的混球
Why, you dirty...
回答 赖瑞 赖瑞?
Come in, Larry. Larry?
赖瑞?
Larry?
你抓到了他吗?
Did you get him, Larry?
我想赖瑞抓到了他
I think Larry got him.
- 警长... - 赖瑞 回答
- Sheriff... - Attaboy, Larry.
回答 赖瑞?
Come in. Larry?
警长
Sheriff...
我现在逮到你了
I got you now.
斜背着
Lean over.
达令
Darling...
我们为何在白屋旅馆新婚套房
Why are we suddenly staying in the bridal suite of the Whyte House?
象征我们的合作无间 甜心
In order to form a more perfect union, sweetheart.
詹姆斯
James...
我终于可以叫你詹姆斯了吗?
May I finally call you James?
我会怎么样呀?
What's going to happen to me?
你和你朋友非利提过我吧!
You did talk to your friend Felix about me?
他怎么说?
What did he say?
20年到无期 没什么很严重的
Something about 20 years to life. Nothing important.
- 20年到无期?! - 别紧张 达令
- 20 years to life?! - Relax, darling.
这能因情况而异
I'm on top of the situation.
乔斯夫妇
Mr and Mrs Jones?
对 登记本上是这么写的
Yes, that's the name on the register, Mr Leiter.
- WW怎么样? - 华盛顿说不行
- What's the score with WW? - Washington says no go.
- 我们目前按兵不动 - 按兵不动?
- We sit still for now. - Sit still?
帝凡内乔斯则预约好了 终身要住另一间旅馆
And Miss Tiffany Case "Jones" has a lifetime reservation at another hotel.
政府经营的
The kind the government... runs.
我很合作 莱特先生
I'm cooperating, Mr Leiter.
我真的很合作
Really I am.
我可以作证
I can vouch for that.
非利 这并不是真的白宫 他也不是总统
Felix, this is not the real White House, and he's not the president.
- 我们干脆就去见他呀! - 总统我倒能让你见
- Why don't we go and see him? - The president I can get you in to see.
但是在华盛顿相信怀特是贼之前 我们只能这样
But until Washington believes Whyte's a thief, that's the way it is.
在这同时 我相信你和乔斯太太
In the meantime, I'm sure you and  "Mrs Jones"...
能够找出自娱之道
can find some way to amuse yourselves.
还有务必别打扰楼上那快乐的人
And just to make sure you're not disturbed, I have a man upstairs.
还有汉密尔顿就在外面
And Hamilton... is right out here.
再见 詹姆斯
So long, James.
- 这倒是个改变! - 什么?
- Well, that's a switch! - What's that?
三只小猪保护狼
The wolf being guarded by the three little pigs.
我很快就回来 达令
I won't be long, darling.
你去哪里?
Where are you going?
上楼一下
I'm just popping upstairs for a moment.
- 16楼? - 不 小姐 只到最顶端
- Sixteenth floor? - No, lady. Starlight Lounge only.
好了 站开门边 要上了
OK, folks. Stand clear of the doors. Here we go.
顶端到了 在左边 有阶梯
Starlight Lounge to the left. Express to street level only, folks.
好了 站开门 走了
OK. Stand clear of the doors. Here we go.
欢迎你 孩子 我们还等着你呢
Howdy, son. We've been expectin' you.
先处理你的私人之事
You got any personal business to take care of in there,
再谈正事
you go right ahead.
首先我怀疑你带了武器
First, I suspect you're wearin' a hog leg.
你介意站起来 把它拿掉吗?
Would you mind standin' up and takin' it off?
太好了
Isn't that nice?
你是个聪明的人
You are a pleasant fella.
你进来呀 孩子
Why don't you just come on in, son?
放轻松 别客气
Relax. Make yourself comfortable.
这就对了 就从那边
That's good. Right on over there.
晚安 邦德先生
Good evening, Mr Bond.
布洛费
Blofeld.
晚安 007
Good evening, 007.
双重危险 邦德先生
Double jeopardy, Mr Bond.
恐怕你只是杀了我另一个替身
You killed my only other double, I'm afraid.
他死了之后 志愿者 可以理解地 变得很害怕
After his death, volunteers were, understandably, rather scarce.
真是可惜 花了那么多的时间及金钱
Such a pity. All that time and expense
只是提供你一个虚幻的英勇时刻
simply to provide you with one mock-heroic moment.
我是威乐.怀特
Willard Whyte speakin'.
是的 州长 我接到你的口信
Yes, Governor. I got your message.
不 不 要我出席不太可能
No, I'm afraid a personal appearance is quite out of the question.
我会派人送去预付款的
I'll send a deposition to the committee.
谢谢 州长
Thank you, Governor.
这一招高明
Well, that's a neat trick.
一个声音器
A voice box, Mr Bond.
科学从来不是我的特长
Science was never my strong suit,
但是原理是很简单
but the principle is easy enough.
把人的声音型态及共鸣
Someone's voice patterns and resonance
存入声音记号的小录音带
stored in a small oral-signature tape.
一个小型电晶体的变体 再植入他的颈子里
And a miniature, transistorised version is installed in his neck.
还是他的颈子 我不记得
Or is it "his" neck? I never can remember.
总之 这不重要 我们二个声音都一样
Anyway, no matter. We both sound alike.
我向二位恭喜
My congratulations to you both.
很不错的小公司
Nice little company.
爆炸物 石油 电子 建筑 航空
Explosives, oil, electronics, houses, aviation.
我也作得很不错
I've done rather well with it, too.
维持得很好 但实际上怀特是很棒企管人才
Tried to cut some of the fat off, but Mr Whyte's a splendid administrator.
公司自己就能运作呢
Damn thing runs itself.
我想你杀了他
I suppose you killed  "him".
没这么戏剧化
Nothing so melodramatic.
我只是将他予以保存
I'm simply holding him in cold storage, so to speak.
防止外界干扰我计划的保险政策
An insurance policy against any outside interference with my plans.
他确是理想的绑架受害者 人们五年未见到他了
The ideal kidnap victim. No one's seen the man for five years.
所以谁会想念失踪的人
Who'd miss someone who's already missing?
你真聪明 邦德先生
How clever you are, Mr Bond.
既然你并未失去你的过人智慧
Nice to see you haven't lost that fine mental edge, 007.
请不要有愚呆的念头
Please don't get any foolish notions.
认为那飞弹不是实用性的武器
That missile is not a practical weapon.
也不值得我浪费工夫
Well, it's hardly worth the effort.
毕竟我不知道该杀你们那一位
After all, I wouldn't know which one of you to kill.
我们了解你的困境
We appreciate your predicament, Mr Bond.
我们深感同情
We deeply sympathise.
很高明的主意
Right idea, Mr Bond.
但看错了猫
But wrong pussy.
我确实很高兴我们今天的会面
I do so enjoy our little visits, Mr Bond.
但是不论这将令人多难过
However potentially painful they may be.
这次的会面要结束了
But I'm afraid this one has come to an end.
你打算如何处理那些宝石
What do you intend to do with those diamonds?
非常好的问题
An excellent question.
也是将吊悬全世界之上的问题
And one which will be hanging on the lips of the world quite soon.
如果我要公布这一件事
If I were to break the news to anyone,
一定第一个告诉你 你也知道
it would be to you first. You know that.
但时间晚了 我也累了
But it's late, I'm tired,
我还有很多事要作
and there's so much left to do.
晚安 邦德先生
Good night, Mr Bond.
去呀! 去呀! 只是部升降
Well, go on, go on. It's merely a lift.
或者我该说电梯
Or perhaps I should say "elevator".
不论如何
In any event, I'm sure you'll find it much more convenient
会比你在旅馆外面攀沿要方便多
than mountaineering about outside the Whyte House.
按L的键
You press L, Mr Bond.
但字可能不是以L开头
The word "lobby" begins with L.
如果我们第一次就得手 其先生
If at first you don't succeed, Mr Kidd...
再试一次 温先生
Try, try again, Mr Wint.
我们二个之中有人好难闻
One of us smells like a tart's handkerchief.
恐怕是我 味道还未消失
I'm afraid it's me. Sorry about that, old boy.
我不介意那机器一天坏二次
I don't mind the cockamamie machine breaking down twice a day.
但为何在离最近出口五百码远?
But why the hell does it always have to be 500 yards away from the nearest hatch?
好了 查理 这回轮到你扮它背
All right, Charlie. It's your turn to play hunchback.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
我在溜鼠 但似乎迷了路
I was just out walking my rat and I seem to have lost my way.
我是威乐.怀特
Willard Whyte speakin'.
我是伯特
This is Bert.
我们有问题了
We got a problem.
你的声音怎么了 感冒了吗?
What's wrong with your voice? Got a cold?
别管这个了
Never mind about that.
我刚看到邦德在赌场内
I just saw James Bond in the casino.
- 不可能的 - 你自己来看吧!
- That's impossible. - Come and see for yourself.
听着
Hey, listen.
如果他有一半别人说得那么厉害 我们真得有麻烦了
If he's half the genius they say he is, we're in for real trouble.
- 冷静 伯特 - 他一定不是一个人行动
- Calm down, Bert. - It's a cinch he's not working alone.
这地方一定满布警探
This place must be crawling with agents by now.
- 我们最好迁走怀特 - 胡说
- I think we should move Willard Whyte. - Nonsense.
怀特先生在他的别墅内安全得很
Mr Whyte is perfectly safe at his own summerhouse.
在城外十里的小山上
It's on the ridge, about ten miles out of town.
我有点惊奇 伯特 这不像你呀! 会惊慌
I'm a little surprised, Bert. It's not like you to panic.
我只是很不喜欢 和邦德这样厉害的人打交道
I just don't enjoy messing around with a guy as tough as James Bond.
别管詹姆斯邦德 你马上到那别墅去
Never mind James Bond. You get down to that house.
我想怀特先生突然失去利用价值
I'm afraid Mr Whyte has suddenly outgrown his usefulness.
- 要作得干净些 伯特 - 不要担心
- Do it cleanly, Bert. - Don't worry.
把一切事交给我
Just leave everything to me.
这可笑的装置真得有效呢 Q
That ridiculous contraption actually seems to work, Q.
这次你超越自己了 才不呢
You've surpassed yourself this time.
我去年圣诞就替孩子作了这个
Not a bit of it. Made one of these for the kids last Christmas.
麦斯 我及詹姆斯前往别墅
Maxwell, James and I will head for the house.
等我们一到别墅你就到顶楼去
Get set to hit the penthouse as soon as we find Whyte.
我找麦斯
Let me speak to Metz.
计划有所改变 要加快在24小时内完成作业
There's been a change. Push all plans forward by 24 hours.
我马上到你那边去
I'm joining you immediately.
给我5分钟上去 5分钟找怀特
Give me five minutes to get up there and five minutes to find Whyte.
你确信你知道你自己在作什么
Are you sure you know what you're doing?
十分钟后再问我
Ask me again in ten minutes' time.
叫麦斯准备冲入顶楼
Tell Maxwell to stand by to hit the penthouse.
嘿 在这儿
Well, hi there!
我叫班比
I'm Bambi.
早安... 班比
Good morning... Bambi.
我是桑普
And I'm Thumper.
我们能为你效劳吗?
Is there something we can do for you?
我能想出好几件事
I can think of several things offhand but
但目前我要找威乐.怀特
at the moment I'm looking for Willard Whyte.
威乐呀!
Oh, Willie.
他就在那边
Why, he's right out there.
那这边就没事了?
And that's all there is to it?
并不尽然
Not quite.
首先 我们二个要玩一玩
First... we're gonna have a ball.
或者你的班比!
All yours, Bambi!
又到你了 班比
You're on again, Bambi!
桑普
Thumper...
非利
Hello, Felix.
你不会知道 怀特就要被杀
Willard Whyte is about to be executed,
你看谁还在这里教换气
and guess who's giving breaststroke lessons.
- 怀特在哪里? - 我还未查到
- Where the hell is Whyte? - I haven't found out yet.
仍然没查到
Still haven't found out.
好的
Right!
联邦调查局?
FBI?
- 中情局? - 不 中情局
- CIA? - No. CIA
不 英国情报局 怀特先生 詹姆斯邦德
British Intelligence, Mr Whyte. James Bond.
看来你遇见了我的二位朋友 班比和桑普
I see you've met my friends, Bambi and Thumper.
对 我们小聊一番
Yes, we did have a bit of a chat.
我到底发生什么事我该怎么办?
What the hell's happened to me and what can I do about it?
我们先离开这里路上向你解释
Let's get out of here first and I'll explain it to you en route.
叫麦斯进攻顶楼
Tell Maxwell to hit the penthouse...
沙斯比
Saxby.
- 伯特.沙斯比? - 对
- Bert Saxby?! - Yeah.
告诉他 他被开除了
Tell him he's fired.
Q先生 你有没有收获呀?
Hi there, Mr Q. Are you having any luck?
我是蛮有收获的 谢谢
I'm being somewhat successful, thank you.
Q先生 请问你听到
Listen, Mr Q. I... I was wondering.
别人谈起我的事吗?
Have you heard any talk about me
听非利或詹姆斯谈起?
from Felix or James?
恐伯没有
No, I'm afraid not.
我想我现在是替好人工作了
I guess I'm working for the good guys now,
但我还是在进牢狱的关口 他们仍然要抓我
but I'm two steps away from the slammer if they want me there.
我想… 也许你能替我说好话
I thought... you might be able to put in a good word.
真不可思议
That's unbelievable!
依我的电子磁性RPM控制器
An electromagnetic RPM controller.
我一直就想试试看 是这样的
Been aching to give it a try. You see,
利用磁性使压力松解
pressure on the case when the desired symbols appear
这会引起内部的圆筒转动 就在适当时
causes the rotation of the cylinders to stutter at the precise moment needed to...
要计程车吗? 小姐
Cab, lady?
看看猫吸引了什么来呀!
Well, well, well. Look what the cat dragged in.
很高兴见到你 凯斯小姐
I'm delighted to meet you, Miss Case.
我好怕这次沉闷的旅行…要我单独渡过呢
I'd so dreaded the prospect of making this tedious journey alone.
这边请
This way, Mr Whyte.
就在这儿的呀
It was right here.
大约六尺高 扇形的板
About six feet high, with a solar panel.
- 上面是薄的金底画出来 - 给我
- It had these aerofoils that seemed to... - Draw it for me.
麦斯博士是你请的人吗?
Was Dr Metz on your payroll, Mr Whyte?
不是 但我听过他 从来不是我们这行的朋友
No. But I heard of him. Everybody in our business has.
是世界第一流的雷射光折射专家
The world's leading expert on laser refraction.
致力于和平的理想主义者
A committed idealist to peace.
布洛费是怎么让他来工作的 我看我永远不会知道!
And how in the hell Blofeld got his hooks in him, I will never know!
他当初怎么能通过安全检查到这里工作的?
How did he get security clearance to work here in the first place?
是你说的呀 我亲自和你谈过呀
From you, sir. I talked to you personally about it.
我刚才就认出你的声音
I even recognised your voice just now.
我想我一定告诉你
I'm sure I must've told you
不要保留作业的微缩影片纪录
not to keep the usual duplicate microfilm records of the project.
正是 先生
Exactly, sir.
汤母 我叫你如何处理这个
Tom, what did "I" tell you to do with this?
送到笛班勃
Send it to Vandenberg, sir.
快打电话给他们
Well, get 'em on the phone now!
什么?
Yeah?
你一定不相信
You won't believe this.
- 威乐.怀特找你 - 喔
- Willard Whyte for you! - Wow.
- 我真荣幸 - 闭上你的荣幸
- This is a real honour, sir. - Shove your honour!
- 我送去那边的卫星呢? - 24分钟前升空了
- Where's that satellite I sent down there? - Blasted off 24 minutes ago, sir.
完美的升空 所有系统都正常 预计准时完成
Perfect trajectory. All systems go. We expect to enter orbit right on the nose.
- 等一等 发生了事情 - 等一下 怀特先生
- Wait. Something's happened. - Just a moment.
扫描器失去控制
The scanners have gone crazy.
- 第一阶段分离提早进行! - 这没道理呀!
- Premature first-stage separation! - It doesn't make sense!
准备破坏它
Stand by to abort!
我们无法控制它 先生
We can't control it, sir.
破坏它!
Abort it!
不行
It's negative.
我们不能 引导系统被人控制了!
We can't. Something's taken over the guidance system!
它完全自己操作了
It's as if it had a will of its own.
此刻我们什么办法也没有
And there's not a damn thing we can do about it.
我们正在努力 我等一下再打给你 怀特先生
We're working on it. I'll call you back, Mr Whyte.
不管在玩什么花样 现在是你的朋友布洛费在控制了
Whatever it is, your friend Blofeld's controllin' it now.
相当多数量的宝石 由光折射专家在操纵着
A vast supply of diamonds manipulated by an expert in light refraction.
第一个经由宝石引动的雷射光束 而假如这整个玩意儿
The first laser beam was generated through a diamond.
有其传闻力量的十分之一
And if old Metz deserves his reputation,
那这光束可是力量惊人
the power of that thing could be incredible.
而布洛费掌握着它
And Blofeld's got it.
- 它现在在哪里? - 向北达科州接近
- Where is it now? - Approaching North Dakota.
警告战
Alert Strategic Air Command.
我接SAC
Gimme an open line to SAC.
(战略防空中心 北达科州)
所有人员注意 所有人员注意
Attention all personnel. Attention all personnel.
现在是红色警戒 准备紧急程序
We have a red alert. Stand by for emergency procedure.
威乐.怀特
Willard Whyte.
是的 将军
Yes, General.
我们一个飞弹意外地爆炸了 在北达科州
One of our missiles just "accidentally" blew up in North Dakota.
不管是什么事 己开始了
Whatever's happenin', Mr Bond, has started.
- 这是你来之处 - 怀特先生 是的 华府来电
- Is this your herd? - Mr Whyte, phone call from Washington.
- 很紧急 - 我马上来
- Urgent. - I'll catch it in the john.
- 布洛费呢? - 没有踪影
- What about Blofeld? - Not a trace.
但我们发现一个地道 正在调查
We found a tunnel. We'll check it out.
- 帝凡内呢?  - 你不介意我们先找布洛费吧!
- Where's Tiffany? - Do you "mind" if we find Blofeld first?
走! 我们到地道去
Come on! Let's hit that tunnel!
华府刚接到你那养猫朋友的口信
Washington just got word from your friend with the cat.
你相信吗? 他拿我们这整个国家当威胁工具
Would you believe that this whole damn country is bein' held for ransom
要我们明天中午前付赎金
and we've got till noon tomorrow to pay up?
原来是这样 我相信你们不会孤单的
So that's it. Well, I'm sure you won't be alone.
一场国际拍卖
An international auction,
出价最高者能获得核子至尊地位
with nuclear supremacy goin' to the highest bidder.
告诉我 要控制那卫星需要什么?
Tell me, what does he need to control that satellite?
一组简单的控制带输入电脑存库
A simple set of tapes fed into a computer bank.
他们只需要造一个就行了
All he really needs is a building.
这些带子大还是小?
And these tapes? Large or small?
任何尺寸都行
Conceivably any size.
从六英寸到一般录音带
From six inches to a cassette.
假定他仍然用你企业王国作掩护
Assuming he's still using your empire as a cover,
布洛费可能在这地图上任何地方
Blofeld could be anywhere on this map.
从阿拉斯加到佛罗里达
From Alaska to Florida.
从緬因州到奥瑞冈
From Maine to Oregon.
从德州到加州巴哈
From Texas to... Baja California.
巴哈?!
Baja?!
我在巴哈并没有事业!
I haven't got anything in Baja!
北达科州苏俄发生核子意外事件
There is still no official explanation
仍然无官方正式说明
of the apparent nuclear accidents in North Dakota and Russia.
总统府新闻秘书约翰.山那拒绝评论未经证实之报告
Presidential news secretary John Fenner refused comment on a report
亦即各部首长正在开紧急会议
that an emergency meeting of the Joint Chiefs of Staff is in session.
据信美苏二个互相以热线保证
It is believed the United States and the Soviet Union have assured each other
并无发动任何攻击
that no offensive action has been taken by either nation.
另一件在中国发生的核子事件尚未证实
Reports of another nuclear accident in Red China are as yet unconfirmed.
我们将继续报告…又有两只浅水船在十里外就位
Two more submarines have taken up position not ten miles away.
那些军机也不会永远静止不动
Are those military aircraft going to stand off forever?
要是他们不接受我们的最后通告决定攻击 怎么办呢?
What if they won't accept our ultimatum? What if they attack?
冷静 麦斯 这些可笑的虚张声势早在预期中
Calm yourself, Metz. This farcical show of force was only to be expected.
是的 但…用强大力量显示他们的军事肌肉
The Great Powers flexing their military muscles
就像海滩上那些无能的男孩
like so many impotent beach boys.
我很遗憾威胁要摧毁主要城市
I deeply regret my threat to destroy a major city unless they give in,
但除非他们屈服 我也只有这么做了
but the nuclear powers, like all bullies, can only be intimidated by force.
- 但你怎能… - 据他们回答时间还不到一小时
- But how can you... - They still have an hour left to reply.
再一小时就能达到我们共同的梦想 完全的武装解除
One hour for both of us to achieve our common dream: Total disarmament
及世界和平
and peace for the world.
- 有一架飞机飞近 - 距离?
- Sir, there's a single plane approaching. - Range?
两里 继续接近
Two miles, and closing.
发出一号警报
Stage One alert, please.
指挥中心
Command Centre.
实施一号戒备
All crew to Stage One.
到顶端 第二平台
Up the top! Second platform!
来了
There he is!
- 发射! - 不要开枪!
- Aim! - Hold your fire!
所有搜索人员 到甲板上 待命
All recovery crew personnel, proceed to docking level and stand by.
早安 各位! 我是污染公害调查员
Good morning, gentlemen! The Acme Pollution Inspection.
我们要清除污染油源 我们想从这只船开始
We're cleaning up the world. We thought this was a suitable starting point.
多么令人失望! 我期望起码是一国首长
How disappointing! I expected one head of state, at the very least.
说来我们根本不必协商
Surely you haven't come to negotiate, Mr Bond?
你的小岛国甚至未被威胁呢
Your pitiful little island hasn't even been threatened.
彻底搜他的身 然后把他带来见我
Search him from his toenails to the last follicle on his head. Then bring him to me.
我真讨厌进行曲
I do so hate martial music.
正如以往 邦德先生 你完全想对了
As usual, Mr Bond, you were absolutely right.
你猜对了 那个箱子装着卫星主控带
You guessed correctly that that box contained the satellite control tape
你上船来 希望用这个代替
and you came aboard presumably hoping to substitute this
真的控制带
for the real thing.
很抱歉破坏你的主线计划
So sorry to have ruined the line of your suit for nothing.
说到线 你是用什么线控制了凯斯小姐?
Talking about lines, which one did you use on Miss Case?
凯斯小姐对此事采取非常理性的态度
She has taken a reasonable attitude.
正如同所有明理的人 他只有在被威胁时才威胁我
Like any sensible animal, she's only threatening when threatened.
看来你是完全当握了
Well, it appears that you're holding all the aces.
- 这位火龙女 - 嫉妒我? 邦德先生
- Right down to the dragon lady here. - Jealousy? From you, Mr Bond?
你让我受宠若惊呢
I'm flattered.
据我的理智观察:
As La Rochefoucauld observed:
谦虚是最糟的一种自负
"Humility is the worst form of conceit."
我的确希望胜利
I do hold the winning hand.
你何不让我带你参观一下
Why don't you let me take you on a little tour of our facilities?
你有机会再度看到真的控制带
Your chance to see the real tape once again.
我可以跟去吗? 恩斯?
Can I tag along, Ernst?
我会先在比基尼外面加上衣服的
I'd put something on over that bikini first, my dear.
我到达这个阶段了不能让我的部下到头来
I've come too far to have the aim of my crew
看到美的身材而受影响
affected by the sight of a pretty body.
还是没有任何消息!
No word yet from anyone!
只剩十二分钟了
Only 12 minutes left.
好吧! 我想需要一点轻微的刺激了
I suppose a little gentle prodding is called for.
是这样 邦德先生 目前卫星正在
As you see, Mr Bond, the satellite is at present over
肯撒斯上方
Kansas.
但是如果我们摧毁肯撒斯 世界可能几年内都不知道
If we destroy Kansas, the world may not hear about it for years.
或许纽约如此交通繁忙的都市
Perhaps New York. All that smut and traffic.
会给他们重新开始的机会
It would give them a chance for a fresh start.
华盛顿 太好了
Washington, DC. Perfect.
既然我们没有他们的消息 他们会听到我们的消息
Since we have not heard from "them", "they" will hear from "us".
- 去办吧 麦斯 - 华盛顿 好
- See to it, Metz. - Washington. Right.
这大概就是电脑存库 和装密码的带子
And this, presumably, is the control bank with the coded tape.
又说对了 邦德先生
Right again, Mr Bond.
所有卫星是由密码带控制
All satellites are controlled by a coded tape.
秘决就在知道它的密码
The trick is, of course, to have the code.
显然是了
Obviously.
这看起来非常简单 只要按这个开关它就跳出来
It all seems so perfectly simple. I suppose one just presses that and out it pops.
把它放回去
Put it back, Mr Bond.
马上放回去
Immediately.
恩斯
Hi, Ernst.
超人给你惹麻烦了吗?
Is Superman giving you any trouble?
放回去 小心地
Put it back... very carefully.
你开始令人厌烦了 邦德先生
You've suddenly become tiresome, Mr Bond.
目标设定 开始倒数
Target fixed! Commence countdown!
十分钟 开始数了!
Ten minutes and counting!
把他带走 到仓库
Take him away and throw him in the brig.
为保险起见 再搜他一次身
And search him again, just to make sure.
臭女人
Bitch!
快走!
Come on!
现在你担心的问题都丢在身后了
Your problems are all behind you now.
阻止他
Stop him!
9分钟 继续倒数
Nine minutes and counting.
我做到了 我把带子换过来了
I did it. I switched the tape in the machine.
你这呆女人真的带子又放回去
You stupid twit. You put the real one back in.
好了 我们走
Come on, let's go!
气象气球!
A weather balloon!
- 你认为如何? 赖特先生? - 那一定就是信号了
- What do you think, Mr Leiter? - That must be the signal.
这附近二百里内没有低气压呀 我们走!
There isn't a low-pressure area within 200 miles of here. Let's go!
查理一号呼叫飞行小队
This is Charlie One to Squadron.
查理一号呼叫飞行小队 准备作战向目标前进
Charlie One to Squadron. Ready all guns and proceed to target.
我再说一次 向目标前进
I repeat: Proceed to target.
知道 查理一号 完毕
Roger, Charlie One. Out.
加油邦德 快脱身
Come on, Bond. Get the hell off that rig.
八分钟 继续倒数
Eight minutes and counting.
身分不明飞机向我们接近 距离 五里
Unidentified aircraft approaching rapidly. Range... five miles.
但我不明白!
But I... I don't understand!
- 你说他们不会攻击! - 那汽球是个信号
- You said they wouldn't attack! - The balloon was a signal.
那些混蛋 一定以为邦德完成任务
The stupid fools must think Mr Bond has accomplished his mission.
- 开动防卫措施 - 开动防卫措施
- Activate defences! - Activate defences.
七分钟 继续倒数
Seven minutes and counting.
这里是查理一号
This is Charlie One.
开始攻击!
Commence attack!
六分钟 倒数
Six minutes and counting.
用无线电通知他们 布洛费
Get them on the radio, Blofeld!
- 说我们投降 - 投降?
- Tell them we give up! - Give up?
我等这个时刻等好久了
I've waited too long for this moment.
他们要为愚弄我付出重大代价
They'll pay dearly for making a fool out of me.
我现在明白了 你根本不在乎世界和平
I see it all now. You don't give a damn about peace!
- 你只在乎… - 麦斯 闭嘴
- All you care about... - Shut up, Metz.
帝凡内 亲爱的
Tiffany, my dear.
今天要比平常勇敢 是吗?
We're showing a bit more "cheek" than usual, aren't we?
把他带下去 和邦德先生锁在一起
Take her below and lock her up with Mr Bond.
多么可惜 这么一个美人
What a pity. Such nice cheeks, too.
有脑袋就好了
If only they were brains.
毁掉这个 麦斯
Destroy this, Metz.
五分钟 继续倒数
Five minutes and counting.
四分钟 继续倒数
Four minutes and counting.
告诉他们我们要投降! 这全然疯狂了!
Tell them we surrender! This is utter madness!
你再说一句 我就杀了你 回到你的工作区
One more word, Metz, and I'll have you shot! Get back to your post!
马上准备好我的战斗浅水船
Prepare my bathosub immediately.
三分钟 继续倒数
Three minutes and counting.
所有系统设定
All systems interlock.
升降机启动浅水船开始作业
Bathosub to crane. Commence lift.
二分钟 继续倒数
Two minutes and counting.
动力读表系统开了
Power and breathing systems on.
释放装置开了
Release catch is open.
把船降下
Lower away.
快开升降机! 把船降下!
Bathosub to crane! Lower away!
醒醒 家伙! 把船降下!
Wake up, man! Lower away!
你这白痴! 你差一点害死我!
You stupid idiot! You could've killed me!
松船放开!
Disengage!
降落! 不是上升!
Lower! Not up!
一分钟 倒数
One minute and counting.
布洛费呼叫指挥中心!
Blofeld to Command Centre!
回答!
Come in!
布洛费呼叫指挥中心!
Blofeld to Command Centre!
回答!
Come in!
可恶的家伙!
Damn you!
指挥中心 告诉我!
Command Centre, come in!
四十秒
40 seconds and counting.
给我那个
Get the gun.
- 拿去! - 扫射他们!
- Here! - Shoot 'em!
跳!
Jump!
十...九...
Ten... nine...
再见 詹姆斯! 我会通报M 你在回程中
So long, James! I'll wire M you're on your way home!
不要告诉他们我们往那个方向!
Don't tell him which direction we've taken!
如果你们玩得很愉快
If you're havin' a good time,
让船长依着圈子航行!
let the captain know and I'll have him steam around in circles!
詹姆斯 有一件很重要的事我一直要问你
James, there's something very important I've been meaning to ask you
关于我们
about us.
我知道以我们这样的关系 不该由女孩子来问
I know in a relationship like ours, the girl's not supposed to be the one to ask.
但我忍不住
But I can't help it.
还有请回答前
And please
务必三思
think before answering.
我保证
That I promise.
詹姆斯...
James...
这一定是送错了 我并没有叫这些
There must be some mistake. I didn't order anything.
没有错 先生
No mistake, sir.
奉威乐.怀特的指示 以此略表他的敬意
On the specific instructions and with the compliments of Mr Willard Whyte.
新鲜海鲜
Oysters Andaluz.Shashlik.
各种海味
Tidbits.Prime rib "en jus".
沙拉 欧皮
Salade Utopia.
至于点心
And for dessert,
则是比爱思甜点
the "pie de ristance"...
一道绝佳的冰其淋点心
la bombe surprise.
太棒了 里面有什么?
That looks fantastic! What's in it?
夫人 那就不希奇了
But then there would be no "surprise", would there, madame?
- 夫人 要坐下来吗? - 谢谢
- If madam would care to be seated. - Thank you.
我们马上就好 然后就让二位安静地用餐
This will just take a moment, and then we will leave you in peace.
要酒吗? 先生
Wine, sir?
55年分的穆塔洛
Mouton Rothschild '55.
- 可以开始吗? - 请问始
- May we begin? - Please do.
酒选得很好 是吧!
A happy selection, if I may say.
我自会判断
I'll be the judge of that.
味道很强 不是瓶盖 而是你摇得不够
That's rather potent. Not the cork, your aftershave.
强得足以掩盖任何味道
Strong enough to bury anything.
但酒很好
But the wine is quite excellent.
虽然对这样的大餐 我期望的酒是红葡萄酒
Although, for such a grand meal, I had rather expected a claret.
当然
Of course.
不幸是我们酒库红葡萄酒不多
Unfortunately, our cellar is rather poorly stocked with clarets.
穆塔洛就是红葡萄酒
Mouton Rothschild "is" a claret.
而且在摇动之前不太好闻 闻起来味道冲鼻
And I've smelt that aftershave before. And both times I've smelt a rat.
他的确是夹尾巴而逃
He certainly left with his tails between his legs.
哦 詹姆斯!
Oh, James!
对了 你要问我什么?
Oh, yes. What were you about to ask me?
詹姆斯...
James...
我们怎么把那些宝石弄下来?
How the hell do we get those diamonds down again?